# **Bona Brian Siagian**

(+62) 822 1929 8128 • bonabriansiagian@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/bonabrian https://bonabrian.com • https://github.com/bonabrian

### **SUMMARY**

Full-stack engineer with 4+ years of experience using a range of Frontend and Backend technologies like Java/Kotlin (Spring), PHP (Laravel), and Javascript/Typescript (Vue, React). As a Full-Stack Developer, I am responsible for designing, developing, and maintaining software that meets both technical specifications and business requirements. I understand the importance of delivering high-quality products that not only meet technical requirements but also provide tangible business value. To achieve this, I work closely with organizations to understand their unique needs and requirements, and I utilize my technical expertise to deliver customized solutions that drive business outcomes.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Full Stack Engineer at Investree

November 2020 - Present

- Designed, developed, and maintained high-performance, robust, and scalable server-side applications using Kotlin (Spring) for the back-end, PHP (Laravel) for legacy systems, and JavaScript (Vue) for front-end development.
- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams, including designers, product managers, and stakeholders to ensure seamless integration and implementation of new features.
- Developed a flexible and configurable loan automation process that efficiently streamlines business operations, reducing the duration of the process by 61%, resulting in a substantial time reduction from 22.13 hours to 8.70 hours. This improvement increases the business capacity by 175%. Furthermore, the automation eliminates 132 clicks per loan process and replaces 49 manual data inputs.
- Developed and maintained APIs that are widely used by our partners, facilitating seamless collaboration and integration with their systems.
- Contributed to the development of technical standards, best practices, and design patterns.
- Actively participated in code reviews, providing valuable feedback and ensuring adherence to coding standards, best practices, and quality assurance.
- Conducted comprehensive unit testing on all new features and enhancements, ensuring a minimum of 80% coverage for both the back-end and front-end components.
- Resolved technical issues in a timely and efficient manner.
- Deliver delightful UX and performant front-end software.
- Build reusable UI components.
- Centralized structured logging to provide monitoring, auditability, business metrics, and service metrics (Elastic Search, New Relic).
- Continuous integration and delivery with Jenkins and Git.

- Adhered to an agile methodology for the software development process.
- Integrated with various third-party services and APIs, including digital signature, document generation, and payment systems to add additional functionality to applications.
- Maintained and updated documentation for the software development process.

#### Full Stack Engineer at Varnion

June 2018 - August 2020

- Refactored legacy code to adhere to modern design patterns, ensuring the maintainability and longevity of software systems.
- Optimized database structure to improve performance and scalability, reducing latency and downtime.
- Enhanced a network monitoring Telegram bot using PHP (Slim) to improve its functionality and performance.
- Integrated Elasticsearch into our network monitoring system, leading to a 30% improvement in load times and enabling real-time data visualization.
- Created a company profile and careers page using a combination of Javascript frameworks (Vue and React) for the Front-end, and PHP (Laravel) for the API and CMS components.
- Conceptualized and designed innovative features to enhance the company's products, providing a competitive advantage and improved user experience.
- Mentored and provided guidance to junior developers on best practices, coding standards, and software development methodologies.
- Stayed current with emerging technologies and industry trends to continuously improve software systems and capabilities.
- Developed an internal data management application using PHP (Laravel) to effectively handle data-related tasks within the organization.

## **EDUCATION**

### Universitas Komputer Indonesia, Bandung

September 2013 - April 2018

Bachelor's of Information Technology GPA: 3.11/4.0

### **SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: Kotlin, Java, PHP,
  TypeScript, Javascript
- Frameworks: Spring, Laravel, Vue, React,
  Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap

- Tools and Technologies: Git, Jenkins, Postman, Elasticsearch, RabbitMQ
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis
- Testing: Unit Test, Jest, PHPUnit

### **PROJECTS**

### Transaxi (Personal Project)

Transaxi is multi vendor marketplace that I created to improve my full-stack development skill and I work as a full-stack engineer

- Architected system and database structure
- Implemented Midtrans Payment Gateway, Rajaongkir, Google Maps API
- Wrote using Laravel for the Back-end (My plan to migrate using Golang) and Vue. js for frontend
- Using RabbitMQ for the queue system and Redis for caching

#### Yummy Bros (https://yummybros.com), Singapore

Yummy Bros is an on-demand healthy food delivery service that provides Asian dishes that are healthier, nutritionally transparent, affordable, and tasty.

Working as a full-stack engineer

- Coded Storefront using Next.js, applied SSR (Server-Side Rendering)
- Built Back Office (CMS) using React.js
- Currently migrating from Bootstrap to Tailwind CSS framework
- Develop APIs that are used by Storefront and CMS

### Wikas (https://wikas.id)

Wikas is News Portal like kumparan.com

I develop this application using Laravel, Vue.js, and Bootstrap

### Nazar (https://nazar.id)

Nazar is a multi-vendor e-commerce store.

I work as an Android developer

- Developed using Kotlin
- Using Retrofit to communicate with API
- Integrated with 3rd party services like Google Maps, Espay, Rajaongkir

More projects can be found on

bonabrian.com/projects

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Bahasa Indonesia
- English